you've gotta be extra careful
mijika ni aru mono
with the things nearest to you
tsuneni ki wo tsukete inai to
you know the closer you get to something
amari ni chika sugite
the tougher it is to see it
miushinatte shimai sou
explain to me this happiness
anata ga saikin taiken shita
that you just got to experience?
shiawase wa ittai nan desu ka
or maybe you're so blessed
megumare sugite ite
that you can't even remember it
omoidasenai kamo
that you stand here now
ima koko ni iru koto
that you still live and breathe
iki wo shite iru koto
I realised that they all were miracles
tada soredake no koto ga
just by themselves
kiseki da to kidzuku
you've gotta be extra careful
mijika ni aru mono
with the things nearest to you
tsuneni ki wo tsukete inai to
you know the closer you get to something
amari ni chika sugite
the tougher it is to see it
miushinatte shimai sou
you know the closer you get to something
the tougher it is to see it
and i'll never take it for granted
it's fine to say you'll never give up
oi tsudzukete kita yume
and to keep chasing your dreams
akiramezu ni susumeyo nante
but the more time you spend talking big
kirei goto wo ieru hodo
the less you get done
nanimo dekicha inai kedo
I will press that handful of courage against my heart
hito nigiri no yuuki wo mune ni
and with its help survive another day
ashita wo ikinuku tame ni
and i'll never take it for granted
let's go
(ナルト)うわっ!!
ハァ… ハァ…。
"STABILIZE"
《螺旋丸に集中しようとすれば
性質変化が怪しくなる…。
If I focus on the Rasengan,
the Change in Chakra Nature
becomes unstable.
といって 性質変化に集中すれば
螺旋丸が うまくいかねえ…》
However, if I focus on
the Change in Chakra Nature,
the Rasengan doesn't turn out well.
《情けねえ…》
I'm so pathetic...
((カカシ : 四代目 火影を超える忍は➡
It's because I believe...
(お前しかないと
オレは そう信じてるからだ))
you're the only Shinobi who can go
beyond the Fourth Hokage.
That's what I believe.
《カカシ先生が あそこまで
言ってくれたってのに…➡
Here Kakashi-sensei has
such high hopes for me...
オレは 全然 それに
応えちゃいねえ… くっ…》
And I'm not fulfilling his hopes at all...
(ヤマト)どうします？
いったん 中止にしますか？
What should we do?
Should we stop for now?
う～ん…。
(カカシ)アイツが そう言うならな。
If that's what he wants to do...
《オレは… オレは…》
I... I...
クソッ…！
Damn it!
寝てるヒマは ねえってばよ！
I don't have time to just sit around!
多重影分身の術！
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
フゥ… フゥ… フゥ…。
みんな！ 気をつけろ!!
Be careful, guys!
また九尾化してるヤツが
いるってばよ！
There's another one turning
into the Nine-Tails!
フゥ… フゥ… フゥ…。
うわぁ！
うわっ！
ヤマト隊長 ヘルプ!!
Captain Yamato, help!
(カカシ)テンゾウ 来たぞ。
(ヤマト)クソ！
Tenzo, it's the Nine-Tails again!
Damn it!
うわっ！
グァオ…。
ふぅ…。
(カカシ)大丈夫か？
You okay?
(カカシ)螺旋丸に風の性質変化を
加える修業に入って 丸１日。
It's been one full day since
you started training
to add the wind Change in Chakra Nature
to the Rasengan...
影分身は 200人程度。
And you're using around
200 Shadow Clones.
１人での修業時間として
換算すると 4,800時間。
It would take one person
4,800 hours to complete that training...
まだまだ足りないか。
I guess it's still not nearly enough.
けど この修業
チャクラコントロールが ムズすぎて➡
But in this training,
the Chakra control is too hard,
影分身は 200人が限界だってばよ。
and 200 Shadow Clones is my limit...
なんか 永久にできねえ気がする。
I get the feeling...
I'll never be able to do this.
そもそも螺旋丸を作るのに
すっげえ集中力がいんのに➡
It takes a ton of concentration
to form the Rasengan in the first place.
そのうえ
性質変化なんて そんなのムチャだ。
It's too much to try to create
a Change in Chakra Nature
on top of that.
いつになく
弱音吐くねぇ お前らしくない。
You're unusually negative.
It's not like you.
それでも お前は
オレの知ってる うずまき ナルトか？
Is that the Uzumaki Naruto
I know so well?
(サクラ)サイ！
(サイ)風邪ひきますよ。
Sai...
You'll catch a cold.
どうです ナルトは。
How's Naruto doing?
(サクラ)螺旋丸に
性質変化を加えるのは➡
Adding a Change in Chakra Nature
to the Rasengan
想像以上に難しいことみたい。
seems harder than imagined.
(サクラ)もともと
ナルトは 器用じゃないし。
Naruto isn't all that intelligent
to begin with, after all...
だから体で覚える修業方法を
カカシ先生が…。
That's why Kakashi-sensei
is having him learn this way...
(サクラ)
そう ナルトにしかできない修業。
Yeah, training only Naruto can do...
２人に分身すれば
修業の成果は２倍。
Training results are doubled
with two clones,
100人なら 100倍…。
and multiplied by a hundred
with a hundred clones...
でも
性質変化を術に組み込むには➡
But... there's a limit.
It's impossible to advance with
just effort and fortitude
努力や根性だけじゃ
どうにもならない壁があるわ。
when one is trying to incorporate
a Change in Chakra Nature
into a Jutsu...
ましてや 螺旋丸は四代目火影様が
編み出したっていうほどの術。
To say nothing of the fact that
the Rasengan is a Jutsu invented
by the Fourth Hokage.
その術に性質変化を加えるなんて
ナルトには無理なのかも。
It might not be possible
for Naruto to add
a Change in Chakra Nature
to such a Jutsu...
そうだね ナルトはバカだし。
That's right.
Naruto's an idiot, after all...
What?
不器用でガサツなナルトに
チャクラの性質変化を➡
He's clumsy and tactless.
There's no way he could do something
as delicate as
螺旋丸に
組み込むだなんて繊細なことが➡
incorporating a Change in Chakra Nature
into the Rasengan.
できるはずないんだよ そもそも。
それなのに カカシ先生もヤマト隊長も
ずっとつきあっちゃって。
And yet Kakashi-sensei and
Captain Yamato have been
sticking it out with him all this time...
里では 暁対策の
小隊が編成されたっていうのに➡
And here in the village,
they have formed units to fight
against the Akatsuki.
戦力のムダ使いとしか…。
It's just... a waste of manpower.
まったくセンスのない ナルトに
火影様は 何を期待して…。
I don't understand what
the Hokage can expect
from a hopeless guy like Naruto...
それ以上 言ったら
アンタも殴るわよ！
I'll pound you if you say anything else.
アンタに ナルトの何が
わかるっていうのよ！
What do you know about Naruto?!
えぇ そう！
たしかに ナルトは大バカよ。
Yes, Naruto is indeed a real idiot!
不器用で ドジで おたんこなすだわ。
He's clumsy, a goof and a birdbrain!
でも 意外性は人一倍！
But no one does the unexpected
more than him!
これまで 何度も
そんな ナルトに助けられてきた！
He's saved us countless times!
みんなが 絶対できないって
思ってることを覆す！
Every time someone expects him to fail,
he proves them wrong!
それが… うずまき ナルトなの！
That's who Uzumaki Naruto is!
チームメイトなら 覚えておきなさい！
If you're any kind of teammate,
you'll keep that in mind!
何よ ヘラヘラして！ 殴るわよ!!
What're you grinning about?
I'll pound you.
それは勘弁ですよ。
Please, don't do that.
でも 本の知識も
たまには 役に立つものですね。
But sometimes knowledge found
in books really can be useful.
The "Understanding Other
People's Feelings" series...?
"Words Reveal True Feelings..."
サイ あなた…。
Sai, you...
サクラが ナルトを信じているのは
わかっているよ。
I know that you believe in Naruto.
そのサクラを
ナルトは 決して裏切らない。
Naruto will never let you down, Sakura.
なによ… はめたわね！
What...? You tricked me...!
だいたい あの まずい泥ダンゴを
食べ続けて➡
It would be too much for Naruto to bear
if he kept eating those awful mud balls
修業の成果がなかったら
やりきれないよ。 ナルトもね。
and didn't have any results to
show for his training.
泥ダンゴって 何よ！
What do you mean by mud balls?!
効き目を
優先しただけなんだから！
I simply prioritized effectiveness
ahead of taste!
アンタ 人の本心を見抜く前に➡
Before reading into
the true feelings of others...
自分の本心を
言わないほうの勉強しろ！
you should learn how not to talk
about your own!
(サイ)ハハハ… 大丈夫。
ナルトは やり遂げるさ。
It'll be fine! Naruto will pull it off!
ったく…。
For crying out loud...
《ナルト… がんばれ！》
Naruto...
Hang in there!
でも 今回ばかりは ムリだってばよ。
But I don't think it'll work this time...
それでも やらなきゃな。
You have to do it anyway.
だったら カカシ先生は
右 見てるときに➡
Then could you look to the left
while looking to the right
同時に 左を見ろって言われて
できんのかよ!?
if someone told you to?!
《たしかに。 そりゃ ムリだ》
Indeed...
That is impossible.
なるほど。 そういうことか。
I see... That's what this is about...
なら できないこともない。
Then I guess it's not outside
the realm of possibility.
Huh?!
影分身の術！
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
右を見ながら…。
By looking to the left...
左を見るってのは
こういうことだろう？
while looking to the right...
This is what you mean, right?
そっか！
I get it!
《何か わかったの？》
Did he figure something out?
影分身の術！
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
(飛段)二尾の封印のために
わざわざ 呼び戻したのかよ！
You went to the trouble of
calling us back here
just to seal the Two-Tails?
(首領)これから ３日はかかる。
覚悟しておけ。
It will take three days.
Prepare yourselves.
(飛段)３日かよ！
ったくもう なげぇな！
Three days...?
This'll take forever, man.
It's raining over here.
こっちは 雨だぜ！
(角都)飛段 お前が言うな。
Hidan... I don't want to hear
that from you.
(飛段)木ノ葉のヤツら もう少しで
皆殺しにできたんだぜ!?
I was this close to killing
all those Hidden Leaf idiots.
無神論者どもに ジャシン教の存在を➡
And here I was just about to
make those atheists realize
知らしめてやる
ところだったのによ！
the existence of the Way of Jashin!
(首領)木ノ葉は
無神論者ではない。
The Hidden Leaf aren't atheists.
先代を神とし
火の意志を思想に行動する。
They consider their predecessors
as gods
and act based on the philosophy
of the will of fire.
ま そんなものは 戦うための
大義名分だともいえるがな。
Well, I suppose we could
call something like that
a justification to fight.
あぁ!? テメエ それ オレを
バカにして言ってんのか!? あぁ!?
Huh...?!
You jerk! Are you insulting me? Huh?!
(首領)いや… お前の戦う理由を
別段 バカにしたつもりはない。
No... I've no intention of insulting
your reason for fighting in particular.
オレも 同じ穴のムジナだからな。
I'm in the same boat as you, after all.
戦争の理由なんてのは
なんでもいい。
It doesn't matter what
the reason for war is.
宗教 思想 資源
土地 怨恨 恋愛 気まぐれ…。
Religion. Philosophy. Resources.
Land. Grudges. Love.
A whim...
どんな くだらない理由でも➡
No matter how stupid they may be,
戦争するだけの
理由になってしまう。
they're all reasons worth getting
into war over.
戦争は 絶対になくならない。
There will always be war.
理由は後づけでいい。
本能が戦いを求める。
The reason can be dealt with later...
Our Instinct is to seek out battles.
(飛段)
誰も テメエの長ったらしい話は➡
Nobody's listening to
your long-winded speech!
聞いてねえんだよ。 オレには
オレのやり方ってもんがある。
I've got my own way of doing things.
オレ自身の 目的もある。
I've got my own goals.
すべてを組織に委ねるつもりは
ねえからな。
I've no intention of giving up everything
for this organization!
(首領)
暁という組織に属している以上➡
As long as you're affiliated with
the Akatsuki organization,
その目的にも 協力してもらう。
you will collaborate with our goal.
暁の目的が達成されれば➡
Once the Akatsuki's goal is attained,
お前の目的も
すぐに成就するだろう。
your goals will also be realized.
フン あれこれ
かっこつけたところで➡
Heh, you can act cool all you want,
暁の目的は ただの金集めに
なってるじゃねえか。
but that doesn't change the fact that
all the Akatsuki wants
to do is make money!
角都と同じだ。
You're the same as Kakuzu...
戦う理由のなかで
いちばん嫌いなタイプだぜ。
That's the type of reason for fighting
I hate the most.
そうだ
確かに当面の目的は金だ。
You're right...
Our immediate goal is indeed money.
が 本来 暁の目的は
別のところにある。
But the Akatsuki's true goal lies
elsewhere.
その目的のために
莫大な金がかかるのだ。
It will cost a large amount of money
to realize that goal.
オレは トビの次に新入りだからな。
I'm the second newest member
after Tobi,
お前の口から 詳しいことも
聞いたことねえ！
so I haven't heard any of
the details from you.
オレのいねえところで
コソコソと…。
You just plan stuff behind my back...
フッ すねてるのか？
Heh... Are you sulking?
なら そろそろ教えてやろう。
Then I guess it's about time I told you.
暁の最終目的は
段階を踏むことで達成できる。
The Akatsuki's ultimate goal can
be accomplished in steps.
それは 全部で三段階。
And there are three steps in total...
まず第一が 金だ。
The first step is money.
チッ。
そして 第二段階が➡
And the second step is
to use that money
その金を元手に 忍世界初の
戦争請け負い組織を作ることだ。
to create the first war contract organization
in the history of the Shinobi world.
おいおい それじゃあ➡
Come on!
That's the same thing
the other Shinobi villages are doing.
他の忍里のやってることと
同じじゃねえか！
依頼をこなして
報酬を得るってことだろうが！
That's just completing missions
and receiving payment.
テメエは
召し抱えてくれる国もねえ➡
You want to become the leader
of some tiny village that
no land will hire?
小さな里の長にでも
なりてえのか？
くだらねえ！
How stupid...
フッ 国お抱えの里？
A village in service of the land...?
まるで違う。
何？
You've got it all wrong...
What?
順を追って説明してやる。
I'll explain it to you sequentially.
(首領)
強力な 忍里を持つ国にとって➡
In lands with powerful Ninja villages,
the Shinobi business assumes
忍ビジネスは その国の収益において
大きな役割を担っている。
a significant role
in the income of these lands.
忍里は
国内外の戦いに参入することで➡
You could say these Shinobi villages
earn large amounts of money and
莫大な金を稼ぎ➡
support the economy of the lands
by fighting battles
国の経済を支えている
と言っていい。
both within and beyond their borders.
つまり
国が安定した利益を得るには➡
In other words, a certain amount
of war is necessary
それなりの戦争が必要になる。
for a land to obtain stable profit.
しかし 今の時代
小さな戦いこそあれ➡
But in this day and age,
although there are small battles,
かつてのような大戦は
なくなった。
the great wars of the past are gone.
国は 里を縮小し
多くの忍が 行き場を失った。
The lands downsize the villages
and many Shinobi
have nowhere to go.
忍は 戦うために存在する。
Shinobi exist to fight.
国のために
命がけで働いた 見返りが➡
That is why they are rewarded
for risking their lives
この ありさまだ。
for the sake of their land.
忍五大国は まだいい。
The Five Great Nations are fine...
国も里も大きく 信頼もある。
Both the lands and their villages
are large and trusted.
他国からの依頼も多く
安定している。
They receive several missions
from other lands
and are quite stable.
が 小さな国は そうもいかない。
But it doesn't work that way
for the smaller lands.
忍里の保有には 戦時と同じか
それに近いレベルで➡
It costs a lot to maintain
a Shinobi village,
and those costs remain more or less
the same in both war and peacetime.
平時にも莫大なコストがかかる。
だからといって
里を 縮小しすぎれば➡
That being said,
if a village is downsized
too drastically,
突然の開戦に対応できない。
they can't survive if
a war suddenly breaks out.
だから我々 暁が 作るのだ。
So we will mobilize the necessary amount
of Shinobi
国というものに属せず➡
only when needed without allegiance
to a land...
必要なときに 必要なだけの
忍を用意し➡
必要な力をもって
あらゆる小国や小さな里から➡
and create an organization that,
only with the necessary forces,
will take on wars from small villages
and land for money...
金で 戦争を
依頼として請け負う組織。
最初は はした金で
あらゆる戦争を一手に引き受け➡
In the beginning,
we'll fight any war for a small cost
戦争市場を牛耳り
さらには 尾獣を使い➡
and gain control of the war trade.
Then we'll use the Tailed Beasts
to create wars
市場の大きさに合わせて
戦争を引き起こし やがて…。
as big or small as the market requires.
And eventually...
すべての戦争をコントロールし
独占支配する。
we'll control, and have a monopoly
on all wars!
それにともない
大国の忍里というシステムも 崩壊。
In the wake of this,
the Shinobi village system
of the Great Lands will collapse...
暁を利用せざるをえなくなる。
and they'll have no choice
but to use the Akatsuki...
そして その先にある本当の目的に
我々は たどりつく。
And then we'll reach our true goal,
which lies ahead...
目的の 第三段階。
The third step of our goal...
世界を➡
We will...
征服する。
...take over the world.
(綱手)そうか。
I see...
(コテツ)あの…
紅さんには…。
Umm... about Kurenai-san...
お前たちは 関係者に➡
Contact the relevant parties
about the funeral.
葬儀の連絡をしろ。
紅には 私から…。
I'll tell Kurenai...
No... I'll do it.
(シカマル)いや オレが…。
オレが 伝えます。
I'll tell her.
アスマ隊長からの伝言もあるので。
I have a message for her
from Captain Asuma...
やった！
おう！ なんか➡
Yes!
Yeah! I'm kind of getting
the hang of it!
コツが つかめてきたってばよ。
(カカシ)なるほどね。
お前の思いつきって➡
I see... So that's what
your idea was, huh?
そういうことだったのね。
そもそも 螺旋丸でさえ➡
You formed the Rasengan
by using a clone
チャクラ放出係と 形体変化の係の➡
to handle the Change in Chakra Form
while you released the Chakra.
２人組でやってたからな… お前。
そう ３人目のオレでもって➡
Right! I just needed a third clone
風の性質変化をやる係を
作ればよかったんだってばよ！
to handle the wind Change
in Chakra Nature.
１人で 左右を同時に
見ることができねえんなら…。
If I can't look left and right by myself...
右を見るヤツと 左を見るヤツ。
then I just needed to create clones
その２人に分身して➡
to look left and right and
divide up the responsibility!
役割分担をすりゃいいだけの
話だったんだ。
さっきのオレの影分身が
ヒントになったってわけね。
So my Shadow Clone stunt earlier
gave you a hint, huh?
《とは言っても
それは チャクラと影分身のある➡
That being said,
only Naruto has both the Chakra
and the skill with Shadow Clones
for that method to work.
ナルトだからこその方法論だ。
オレはともかく 四代目であっても
不可能なやり方だ。
I couldn't do it like that.
I bet even the Fourth couldn't.
ったく コイツは！》
But he...
(カカシ)さすがは
意外性ナンバー１の忍者だな。 ナルト。
Just what I'd expect
from the Ninja with
the most unpredictability, Naruto.
なんだかな～ オレは お前のことが
ものすっごく好きになってきたぞ。
I'm not sure how to say it...
I've really started to take a liking to you!
"YIKES!"
いきなり
キモイこと言うなってばよ！
Don't say gross stuff
out of the blue like that, you jerk!
この野郎！ びっくりして
せっかくの術がはじけちまったろ。
The Jutsu I went to the trouble of creating
got messed up because
you freaked me out!
いや そういう意味じゃなくてね。
わぁ 近寄るな！
Uhh, I didn't mean it like that...
Whoa, stay back!
なんていうか その…。
イヤ～！
I don't know quite how to say it...
Well...
No!
(ヤマト)まったく 何やってんだか
あの２人は…。
For crying out loud...
What're those two doing...?
(イズモ)連絡です。
I have a message for you.
ちょっと待てよ！ うん？
Just a minute...
ぐっ！ うん？
なんだろう？
What's going on?
カカシ先輩！ いったん
修業を中止して 里のほうへ。
Kakashi-senpai!
We must stop the training for now
and head back to the village!
なっ！ えぇ～！
いったい 何？
What?!
What the hell is going on?!
猿飛 アスマさんが…。
Sarutobi Asuma-san...
(ヤマト)亡くなりました。
...is dead.
what made me think
kondo wa itsu aeru ka nante
how can you say that with a straight face
sonna kao shite yoku ieru tte
when you asked we will meet again
omotteta yo nande darou
any time you talk to much I don't get it
any time shaberisugi no k y
for a moment I see your bluff and I cry
chirari miseru tsuyogari na i cry
do my tears even work on you?
namida no kouka wa dore kurai
I keep saying "I want to be loved"
watashi nari ni aisaretai
in my own special way but you still don't get the hint
afureru no ni kimi ga mienai
this nagging feeling I feel
nidoto kimi ni aenai
that I'll never see you again...
sonna ki ga suru nda
I wish I could tell you but I can't find the words
tsutaetai no ni umai kotoba miataranai
maybe I'd rather listen to you lie
watashi tabun uso demo ii no ni
I can't even say "don't leave me"
ikanaide mo ienai yo
when you let go of my hand
nigitteta te ga hanaretara
will you forget someday?
kimi wa itsuka wasurechau no
about me
watashi no koto
I wish I could tell you but I can't find the words
tsutaetai no ni umai kotoba miataranai watashi tabun
maybe I'd rather listen to you lie 'cause I can't even say "don't leave me"
uso demo ii no ni ikanaide mo ienai yo
うめぇ～！
そんな 甘ったるいもん
よく食うね。
それより こんなところで
サボってていいのかい？
Next Episode
どうせ戻っても
雑用 押しつけられるだけですよ。
You okay, Konohamaru...?
ここにいたか！ 見つけたぞ コテツ！
しまった！
Uncle Asuma... Why...?!
さっさと仕事に戻れって
綱手様が！
Asuma...
Choji, do you know where Shikamaru is?
頼む！ 見逃してくれ！
ダメだ！ 逃がさん！
It looks like he isn't here yet...
そこをなんとか！
That's strange.
あっ！ 待て コラッ！
And here his mom said he went out
after stopping by the house...
イ… イズモ！
大丈夫か？
Where the hell did he go
at an important time like this...?!
うぅ… コテツ！ あっ ひらめいた！
Team 10
Next time: "Team 10"
っと まあ こんなわけで
オレの 水飴拿原はできたわけさ。
"SYRUP CANDY"
まっ 発想の種なんつうのは
なにげない日常にあるってことだ。
This is good!
How can you eat something so sugary?
(コテツ)お前も がんばって見習えよ。
More importantly, should you really
be goofing off here like this?
帰っていいっすか？
If I go back, I'll just have
odd jobs thrust on me.
So here you are!
l found you, Kotestu!
Uh oh!
Tsunade-sama said for you
to get back to work...
Please! Can't you let me go?!
No way!
You're not going anywhere!
Can't we make this work somehow?
Oh! Hey, wait!
I-Izumo.
You okay...?
Kotetsu!
Oh! I've got it!
Anyway, that's how...
BARBE-Q
I came up with
the Syrup Snare Field.
You can casually find inspiration
in the mundane.
You could learn from
this example.
Can I go home?